Guide to the Horticultural Society of New York Records 1811-circa 2010 (bulk, 1900-circa 2010) MS 3033
New-York Historical Society
- Series VI. Print Matter, 1811-circa 2010; 22.19 Linear feet
  - Subseries VI.A. Hort Periodicals, 1900-1998; 9.08 Linear feet
    - Bulletin, 1970-73 (loose, 3 copies) (3 folders), 1970-1973 (Offsite-box 85, Folder 10-12)
    - Member Newsletter, 1969-1983. (loose, 2 copies) (2 folders), 1969-1983 May (Offsite-box 85, Folder 13-14)
    - Newsletter, 1983-98 (loose, 3 copies) (5 folders), 1983 June-1998 Fall (Offsite-box 85, Folder 15-19)
    - Garden Magazine. List of Articles, 1979-1983, 1984 (Offsite-box 85, Folder 20)
    - Garden Magazine (bound), 1977 November-1978 (Offsite-box 96, Volume HSNY-44)
    - Garden Magazine (copy 2) (bound), 1978 (Offsite-box 96, Volume HSNY-45)
    - Garden Magazine (bound), 1979 (Offsite-box 96, Volume HSNY-46)
    - Garden Magazine (copy 2) (bound), 1979 (Offsite-box 96, Volume HSNY-47)
    - Garden Magazine (bound), 1980 (Offsite-box 96, Volume HSNY-48)
    - Garden Magazine (copy 2) (bound), 1980 (Offsite-box 97, Volume HSNY-49)
    - Garden Magazine (bound), 1981 (Offsite-box 97, Volume HSNY-50)
    - Garden Magazine (copy 2) (bound), 1981 (Offsite-box 97, Volume HSNY-51)
    - Garden Magazine (bound), 1982 (Offsite-box 97, Volume HSNY-52)
    - Garden Magazine (bound), 1983 (Offsite-box 97, Volume HSNY-53)
    - Garden Magazine (copy 2) (bound), 1983 (Offsite-box 97, Volume HSNY-54)
    - Garden Magazine (bound), 1984 (Offsite-box 97, Volume HSNY-55)
    - Garden Magazine (copy 2) (bound), 1984 (Offsite-box 97, Volume HSNY-56)
    - Garden Magazine (loose), 1980-1983, 1986 (Offsite-box 85, Folder 21)
  - Subseries VI.B. Other Hort Print Matter, 1901-circa 2010; 5.85 Linear feet
    The subseries is arranged roughly by the following document types, which are used as headings in the container list: manuscripts and publications; program brochures & pamphlets; forms, invitations & other ephemera; press & publicity; and posters & proclamations.
    The subseries includes a broad range of printed matter, especially ephemera, produced by the Hort over the course of the twentieth century and into the first decade of the twentieth first century. These include informational brochures and booklets, program calendars (ranging from 1933-2006), stationery and forms, membership solicitations, event announcements, admission tickets, press releases, posters, mayoral proclamations, and other documents. Many of these documents date from Hort's earliest years through the 1940s and were found in two (now disbound) scrapbooks. International Flower Shows, New York Flower Shows, lectures, education programs, pilgrimages/tours, exhibitions, and annual and other organization meetings are among the subjects of the material.
    - Manuscripts and Publications (Box -, Folder -)
    - Addresses Before the Horticultural Society, 1923, 1934 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 1)
      Includes "The Future of Nut Growing" (1923) by Robert T. Morris and "Shrubs" (1934) by Arthur Herrington.
    - Manuscript Poems, 1934-1935 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 2)
      Includes "Iussos Asperge Sapores" [about apple trees] sent by Mrs. H.C. Butler, from "Punch, and "I Have a Little Garden" by Benjamin Schloss.
    - A Five Foot Shelf of Garden Books, 1930s-1940s? (Offsite-box 86, Folder 3)
      An annotated bibliography produced by the Hort's Library Committee.
    - Men Who Sought and Found by Ethel W. McCool, 1940s? (Offsite-box 86, Folder 4)
      Compilation of articles on plant exploration written by McCool and originally published for the Hort's Bulletin.
    - Guide to English Gardens by Alice Chauncey, circa 1955 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 5)
      Two copies, both appear to be autographed by the author.
    - "Our Experiences with Orchid Plants in the Home" by Mrs. Thomas Powell, 1962 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 6)
      Includes takeaway notes for a course given at the Hort.
    - Information Bulletins, 1968-circa 1970 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 7)
      Includes articles on horticultural topics, including content for a House Plant Course.
    - Information Sheets, 1970s-1990s (Offsite-box 86, Folder 8)
      Includes various forms of informational articles provided by the Hort on horticulture topics.
    - Miscellaneous Articles, circa 1970s-2000s (Offsite-box 86, Folder 9)
      Includes a small number of tear sheets, clippings, brochures, and other documents on horticulture topics, but which do not appear to relate to Hort itself.
    - "A Horticultural Tour of Gardens Along the Beautiful Great Ouse", 2000 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 10)
      Includes the itinerary and related reading material for Hort's East Anglia tour, with Scott Appell.
    - "A Tour of the Floriade and Private and Public Gardens of the Netherlands", 2002 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 11)
      Includes reading material compiled by Hort Director Education Scott Appell.
    - Doing Time in the Garden: Life Lessons Through Prison Horticulture by James Jiler, 2006 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 12)
      Book is about Hort's GreenHouse and GreenTeam programs concerning vocational training at Rikers Island prison. The N-YHS Library holds another copy of this title under call number F128 HV9306.N6 J55 2006.
    - Program Brochures & Pamphlets (Box -, Folder -)
    - Program Calendars, 1933-1950 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 13)
    - Program Calendars, 1951-1969 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 14)
    - Program Calendars, 1968-1976 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 15)
    - Program Calendars, 1976-1979 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 16)
    - Program Calendars, 1980-1983 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 17)
    - Program Calendars, 1983-1989 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 18)
    - Program Calendars, 1990-1994 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 19)
    - Program Calendars, 1995-1997 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 20)
    - Program Calendars, 1997-2000 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 21)
    - Program Calendars, 2000-2006 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 22)
    - Compleat Gardener Lecture Calendars, 1987-1996 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 23)
    - Central Park Conservancy Program Calendars, 2002-2004 (Offsite-box 86, Folder 24)
      Includes programs offered in partnership with the Hort.
    - Forms, Invitations & Other Ephemera (Box -, Folder -)
    - Early Ephemera, 1902, 1913, undated (Offsite-box 87, Folder 1)
      Includes preliminary programs for the International Conference on Plant Breeding and Hybridization (1902) and a donation form (1913).
    - Scrapbook #1 (5 folders), 1917, 1921-circa 1944 (Offsite-box 87, Folder 2-6)
      Includes contents of a disbound scrapbook, including donation and membership forms, membership solicitation brochures, announcements of lectures, exhibitions and other programs, meeting announcements, etc.
    - Scrapbook #2 (16 folders), 1901-1951 (Offsite-box 87, Folder 7-22)
      Includes the contents of a disbound scrapbook that included certificates, organization constitution and by-laws (as amended over time), invitations, announcements, programs, brochures, admission tickets, and other ephemera related to flower shows, International Flower shows, conferences, pilgrimages, meetings, general organizational matters, various events, membership, etc.
    - Ephemera. General (18 folders), 1970-2010 (Offsite-box 88, Folder 1-18)
    - Ephemera. Membership, 1930s-2000s (Offsite-box 89, Folder 1)
    - Ephemera. Library Benefits, 1994-2004 (Offsite-box 89, Folder 2)
    - Ephemera. Library General, 1990s-2000s? (Offsite-box 89, Folder 3)
    - Ephemera. GreenWorks, 1988 (Offsite-box 89, Folder 4)
    - Ephemera. Stationery, undated (Offsite-box 89, Folder 5)
    - Ephemera. Miscellaneous, 1980s-2000s? (Offsite-box 89, Folder 6)
    - Press & Publicity (Box -, Folder -)
    - Press Releases (2 folders), 1982-1986 (Offsite-box 89, Folder 7-8)
    - Program Updates, 1998-2002 (Offsite-box 89, Folder 9)
    - Press Kits, 1980s-2000s (Offsite-box 89, Folder 10)
    - Publicity Press Book (Clippings, Disbound), 1986-1987 (Offsite-box 89, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous Clippings, 1980-2005 (Offsite-box 89, Folder 12)
    - Posters & Proclamations (Box -, Folder -)
    - Posters. Oversize, 1980-2000 (Drawer OS-Large)
      Includes Houseplant Societies Show "The Joy of Houseplants" (undated), blow-up of Hort advertisement in the New York Times (29 January 1980), New York Flower Shows (1985, 1987/art by Peter Max, 1990/art by Lorenz, 1992, 1995, 1996), Astor Place Flower Market (1982, designed by Susan Keiser), and New York is Book Country (2000, art by Robert Sabuda). There are multiple copies and versions of some of the posters.
    - Mayoral Proclamations (Flat box), 1986-1999 (Offsite-box 108, Folder 2)
      Includes "New York Flower Show Month" (1986 and 1987), "New York Flower Show Days" (1996), and "New York Horticultural Society Centennial Day" (1999) (1980s signed by Edward I. Koch, 1990s by Rudolph W. Giulani).
  - Subseries VI.C. Miscellaneous Print Material, 1811-1997; 7.25 Linear feet
    This subseries includes mid-nineteenth century horticultural publications from the American Institute of the City of New York, and even earlier items relating to the New York Horticultural Society (not be be confused with HSNY), the first such organization in the United States, founded in New York City in 1818. Also found here are visually-interesting seed catalogs from the nineteenth and early twentieth centuries, and various loose botanical prints and engravings.
    The material in this subseries is sorted alphabetically by title or subject.
    - American Institute: Adoniram Chandler, Address, Delivered at the Close of the Nineteenth Annual Fair of the American Institute, of the City of New-York, at Castle Garden, October 23, 1846 (New York: Van Norden & Amerman, 1846). (Offsite-box 78, Folder 1)
    - American Institute: Thomas Bridgeman, Horticultural Report of the Nineteenth Annual Fair of the American Institute, Held at Castle Garden, in the City of New-York, October, 1846 (New York: Van Gelder & Riley, 1846) (Offsite-box 78, Folder 2)
    - American Institute: Thomas Bridgeman and Peter B. Mead, Horticultural Report of the Twenty-First Annual Fair of the American Institute, Held at Castle Garden, New York City, October 1848 (New York: Joseph H. Jennings, 1848). (Offsite-box 78, Folder 3)
    - American Institute: H. Meigs, Address Delivered at the Opening of the Twenty-Second Annual Fair of the American Institute at Castle Garden, October, 1849 (New York: William E. Dean, 1849). (Offsite-box 78, Folder 4)
    - American Institute: Proceedings of the Second Congress of Fruit Growers, Convened Under the Auspices of the American Institute, in the City of New-York, 1849 (Albany: Charles Van Benthuysen, 1850). (Offsite-box 78, Folder 5)
    - American Institute: Schedules of prizes, premiums, programs, etc., 1901-1903 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 6)
    - American Society of Botanical Artists, 2009 Directory of Members (Offsite-box 78, Folder 7)
    - China--A Land of Beauty (Suzhou Gardens), 1960s-1970s (Offsite-box 78, Folder 8)
    - Common Wild Flowers of New York State by Patricia Ellison, John M. Kingsbury, and Peter A. Hyypio (New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences, Cornell University), [1975?] (Offsite-box 78, Folder 9)
    - Eastern New York Horticultural Society: Fifth and Sixth Annual Meetings, 1901-1902 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 10)
      Appears to have been organized in 1896, Hudson River Valley area.
    - Elgin Botanic Garden: David Hosack, A Statement of Facts Relative to the Establishment and Progress of the Elgin Botanic Garden, and the Subsequent Disposal of the Same to the State of New-York (New York: C. S. Van Winkle, 1811). (Offsite-box 78, Folder 11)
      The N-YHS Library holds another copy of this title under call number Y1811 .Hos.
    - A Few Garden Pictures (New York: John Scheepers & Co., Inc., agents for R. Wallace & Co., Colchester, England), circa 1914 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 12)
    - Gourley, Josette (artist), circa 1983 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 13)
      Information about artist Josette Gourley, her painting "Carolina Swamp," and three notecard reproductions of her botanical illustrations.
    - Habit de Jardinier [reproduction antique French engraving], n.d. (Offsite-box 78, Folder 14)
    - Hagan, Patti: gardening articles, 1984-1997 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 15)
      Photocopies of gardening articles by Patti Hagan from the New York Times and Wall Street Journal.
    - Home Landscapes (Westbury, N.Y.: Hicks Nurseries, Inc.), 1938 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 16)
    - Howard Studios Garden Ornaments. Catalogue No. 6., 1934 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 17)
    - Journal of Therapeutic Horticulture, vol. 5, 1990 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 18)
    - Martha Stewart Living, 1998 April (Offsite-box 78, Folder 19)
    - The Mayflower [gardening periodical], 1897 April 18 & May 18 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 20)
    - Metropolitan Urban Garden Festival, April 23-26, 1998, Metro Tech Center, Downtown Brooklyn [flier] (Offsite-box 78, Folder 21)
    - Newport in Flower: A History of Newport's Horticultural Heritage by Harriet Jackson Phelps [draft], 1978 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 22)
      Typescript draft of Phelps's work, published in 1979. Includes correspondence regarding the foreword supplied by Charles D. Webster of the Horticultural Society of New York.
    - New York Florists' Club: Essays and Lectures, 1895, 1901, 1904 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 1)
    - New York Florists' Club: Publications, 1928-1972 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 2)
    - New York Florists' Club: Fiftieth Anniversary of the New York Florists' Club, 1887-1937 [souvenir journal] (Offsite-box 79, Folder 3)
    - New York Horticultural Society: Constitution and By-Laws of the New-York Horticultural Society, Incorporated March 22, 1822 (New York: J. Seymour, 1824) (Offsite-box 79, Folder 4)
      The N-YHS Library holds another copy of this title under call number F126 SB1 .N47 1824.
    - New York Horticultural Society: David Hosack, An Inaugural Discourse, Delivered Before the New-York Horticultural Society at Their Anniversary Meeting, on the 31st of August, 1824 (New York: J. Seymour, 1824). (Offsite-box 79, Folder 5)
      The N-YHS Library holds another copy of this title under call number F126 S93 Box 1.
    - New York Horticultural Society: John Frederick Schroeder, Intellectual and Moral Resources of Horticulture. An Anniversary Discourse, Pronounced Before the New-York Horticultural Society, at the Annual Celebration, August 26, 1828 (New York: the Society, 1828) (Offsite-box 79, Folder 6)
      The N-YHS Library holds another copy of this title under call number Pamph SB105 .S38 1838.
    - New York Horticultural Society: John W. Francis, An Address Delivered Before the New-York Horticultural Society, at Their Anniversary, on the Eighth of September, 1829 (New York: E. Conrad, 1830) (Offsite-box 79, Folder 7)
    - New York Horticultural Society: Monthly Report, 1881-1882 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 8)
      1881: September, October, November, December
      1882: February, March, April, May, September, November
      The N-YHS Library holds six issues from 1885 (February, March, April, May, November, December) under call number F126 SB1.N47 R4.
    - New York Horticultural Society: Illustrations from Frank Leslie's Illsutrated Newspaper, 1856, 1886 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 9)
      1856 July 5: "Exhibition of the N. Y. Horticultural Society at Clinton Hall, N. Y." Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, 5 July 1856 [photocopy; for original, see Box: FF-11, Folder 13]
      1886 November 13: "New York City.--The Eighth Annual Chrysanthemum Exhibition, Under the Auspices of the New York Horticultural Society, at Cosmopolitan Hall, Forty-First Street and Broadway, November 2D-6th."
    - Orchids in the Life and Culture of the Chinese People by Shiu-Ying Hu (Hong Kong: Chung Chi College), 1971 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 10)
    - [Prince] Linnaean Botanic Garden and Nurseries (Flushing, N.Y.: William Prince & Co.): broadside circulars and bill-of-sale, 1826-1878 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 11)
    - Roses by Bobbink & Atkins, 1927 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 12)
    - Roses of Yesterday (Watsonville, Ca.: Lester Rose Gardens), 1948 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 13)
    - Schermerhorn, Richard Jr.: Country Places of Old New York [research paper], n.d. (Offsite-box 79, Folder 14)
    - Seed Catalog (Allen): 1870. Retail Priced Catalogue of Vegetable, Flower, Fruit, Herb and Field Seeds for Sale by R. H. Allen & Co. at Their Agricultural Implement & Seed Warehouses, 189 and 191 Water Street, New-York. (Offsite-box 79, Folder 15)
    - Seed Catalog: Burpee's Farm Annual (Philadelphia: W. Atlee Burpee & Co.), 1884, 1888 (Offsite-box 80, Folder 1)
    - Seed Catalog: Burpee's Farm Annual (Philadelphia: W. Atlee Burpee & Co.), 1895, 1897 (Offsite-box 80, Folder 2)
    - Seed Catalog: Burpee's Farm Annual + Unique List of the Best Seeds That Grow (Philadelphia: W. Atlee Burpee & Co.), 1898 (Offsite-box 80, Folder 3)
    - Seed Catalog: Burpee's Farm Annual (2 copies) (Philadelphia: W. Atlee Burpee & Co.), 1901 (Offsite-box 80, Folder 4)
    - Seed Catalog: Burpee's Annual (Philadelphia: W. Atlee Burpee & Co.), 1919 (Offsite-box 80, Folder 5)
    - Seed Catalog (Gregory): Annual Circular and Retail Catalogue of Warranted Vegetable and Flower Seeds (Marblehead, Mass.: James J. H. Gregory), 1873, 1874 (Offsite-box 80, Folder 6)
    - Seed Catalog: Harlem Nursery. Catalogue of Fruit and Forest Trees, Flowering Shrubs, Evergreens, and Herbaceous Plants (New York: Michael Floy & Sons, 1832). (Offsite-box 80, Folder 7)
    - Seed Catalog (Sawyer): Illustrated and Descriptive Catalogue of Choice and Select Flower and Garden Seeds (Portland, Me. W. C. Sawyer & Co., 1881). (Offsite-box 80, Folder 8)
    - Seed Catalog (Terry): 1891 Seed Annual (Detroit: D. M. Terry & Co., 1891). (Offsite-box 80, Folder 9)
    - Seed Catalog (Thorburn): Annual Catalogue High-Class Seeds (New York: J. M. Thorburn & Co., 1900). (Offsite-box 80, Folder 10)
    - Seed Catalog: Van Bourgondien Bros. 1937 Spring Planting Guide (Offsite-box 80, Folder 11)
    - Seed Catalog: R. A. van der Schoot (Holland) (Offsite-box 80, Folder 12)
    - Seed Catalog: Vick's Illustrated Floral Guide (Rochester, N.Y.: James Vick)., 1873, 1874 (Offsite-box 81, Folder 1)
    - Seed Catalog: Vick's Flower and Vegetable Garden (Rochester, N.Y.: James Vick)., [1880s?] (Offsite-box 81, Folder 2)
    - Seed Catalog (Wayside): Hardy Herbaceous & Alpine Plants (Mentor, Ohio: Wayside Gardens Co., 1928). (Offsite-box 81, Folder 3)
    - Three Hundred Years of Parks: A Timeline of New York City Park History (City of New York, Parks & Recreation), 1988 (Offsite-box 81, Folder 4)
      The N-YHS Library holds another copy of this title under call number F128.64.A1 C32 1988.
    - United States Patent Office: Plant Patents (with illustrations), 1965 (Offsite-box 81, Folder 5)
      2548: Almond tree
      2549: Rose
      2550: Rose
      2551: Crepe Myrtle
      2552: Chrysanthemum
      2553: Rose
      2554: Chrysanthemum
      2555: Chrysanthemum
      2556: Redbud
      2557: Rose
      2558: Rose
      2559: Gladiolus
      2560: Gladiolus
      2561: Gladiolus
      2562: Gladiolus
      2563: Rose, Miniature
      2564: Plum
      2565: Rose
      2566: Ashtree
      2567: Fraxinius
      2568: Azalea
      2569: Rose
      2570: Rose
      2571: Plum
      2572: Cherry
      2576: Rose
      2577: Rose
      2578: Rose
      2579: Rose
    - Wild Flowers of Greece, n.d. (Offsite-box 81, Folder 6)
      Portfolio of twelve loose prints, with captions in Greek.
      01. Anemone coronaria
      02. Vinca herbacea
      03. Crocus aureus
      04. Anemone blanda
      05. Iris attica
      06. Serapias vomeracea
      07. Cistus creticus
      08. Campanula spathulata 09. Lilium heldreichii
      10. Echinops graecus
      11. Dianthus diffusus
      12. Cyclamen graecum
    - [Book] Feasibility Study on the Creation of a City-Wide Plant Information Service, circa 1974 (Offsite-box 81, Folder 7)
    - [Book] Transactions of the Illinois State Horticultural Society, vols. 58-59, 1924-1925 (Offsite-box 82, Folder 1-2)
      The N-YHS Library holds other issues under call number F536 .I26.
    - [Book] The West Point Foundry Site, Cold Spring, Putnam County, New York (Ralph Brill Associates), 1979 November (Offsite-box 82, Folder 3)
      The N-YHS Library holds another copy of this title under call number F129.C648 R3.
    - [Book] The Gardens of Russell Page by Marina Schinz and Gabrielle van Zuylen (New York: Stewart, Tabori & Chang, 1991) (Offsite-box 101, Volume HSNY-108)
    - Botanical illustrations (loose prints & engravings) [Oversize], 1800s (Offsite-box 111, Box FF-11, Folder 2)
      Aquilegia canadensis
      Aralia spinosa (2)
      Arbutus unedo
      Arbutus uva ursi
      Cornus mascula
      Cornus paniculata
      Cornus sanguinea
      Cornus sericea
      Dillenia pentagyna
      Dionae muscipula
      Dodecotheon medea
      Duroia eriopila
      Egle
      Juglans cinerea
      Juglans nigra
      Lathyrus
      Lawsonia
      Ledum latifolium
      Ligusticum scoticum
      Ligustrum vulgare
      Lilium Martagon
      Limodorum
      Limonia
      Lonicera diervilla
      Lonicera media
      Lonicera nigra
      Lonicera periclymenum
      Lonicera sempervirens
      Lonicera symphoricarpos
      Lonicera xylosteum
      Lotus
      Malva
      Manisuris
      Maranta
      Marchantia
      Martynia
      Passiflora
      Pedicularis (2)
      Pelargonium (2)
      Periploca
      Periploca graeca
      Peucedanum
      Phalaris
      Phaseolus
      Phelipaea
      Philadelphus
      Philadelphus coronarius nanus
      Phillyrea
      Phlox (2)
      Phoenix
      Phyllanthus
      Physalis
      Pilularia
      Pimelaea
      Pinguicula
      Pinus (2)
      Pisum
      Pittosporum
      Plantago (2)
      Platanus orientalis
      Platanus orientalis acerifolia
      Plumbago
      Plumeria
      Poa
      Polemonium
      Polianthes
      Polygala
      Polypodium
      Polytrichum
      Pommerullia
      Populus
      Potamogeton
      Pontederia
      Portulaca
      Potentilla
      Primula var.
      Ptelea trifoliata
      Pyrola uniflora
      Ribes lacustre
    - "Exhibition of the N. Y. Horticultural Society at Clinton Hall, N. Y." Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper. [Oversize], 1856 July 5 (Offsite-box 111, Box FF-11, Folder 3)
    - Foster, Laura Louise: Three signed botanical prints (on board) created for the American Rock Garden Society [Oversize], 1981 (Offsite-box 111, Box FF-11, Folder 4)
      Claytonia caroliniana
      Cornus canadensis
      Iris verna
    - "General View of the Central Park, New York." Harper's Weekly. [Oversize], 1860 June 16 (Offsite-box 111, Box FF-11, Folder 5)
    - Goulandris, Niki (artist): Twelve botanical prints. [Oversize], circa 1983 (Offsite-box 111, Box FF-11, Folder 6)
      Gift to HSNY from Mrs. Goulandris, June 1983. Prints are copyright Goulandris Museum (Kifissia).
      01. Anemone pavonina var.
      02. Anemone pavonina var. purpureoviolacea
      03. Cyclamen graecum
      04. Cyclamen repandum
      05. Geranium macrorrhizum
      06. Glaucium flavum var. serpierii
      07. Hablerlea rhodeopensis
      08. Hypericum olympicum
      09. Lilium candidum
      10. Lilium chalcedonicum
      11. Rosa canina
      12. Symphyandra cretica
    - Lilies of Japan (West Orange, N.J.: Joseph Manda Co.) [Oversize] (Offsite-box 111, Box FF-11, Folder 7)
    - Six Fern Botanicals (Victor Schrager and Martha Stewart Living) [Oversize], 1993 (Offsite-box 111, Box FF-11, Folder 8)
      01. Japanese Painted Fern
      02. Trifid Holly Fern & Deceptive Wood Fern
      03. Southern Beech Fern & Eared Lady Fern
      04. Maidenhair Spleenwort, Ebony Spleenwort, Tatting Fern, Holly-Fern Woodsia & Rusty Woodsia
      05. Plumose Oak Fern & Robert's Oak Fern